Guide to the Paul Stephen Galatowitsch Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Paul Stephen Galatowitsch papers
1979-1999
MS 2085
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.26
(23 boxes)
The Paul Stephen Galatowitsch papers consist of research files documenting the AIDS crisis and AIDS response in New Haven in the 1980s and 1990s.
Content Description
The Paul Stephen Galatowitsch papers consist of research files documenting AIDS and AIDS response in New Haven in the 1980s and 1990s. Material includes subject files, interview transcripts, reports related to local AIDS public policy and interventions, papers and presentations, and news clippings and research bibliographies compiled or written by Galatowitsch for his 1996 Yale dissertation, "An Institutional, Organizational, and Cultural Analysis of New Haven, Connecticut's Response to the AIDS Epidemic, 1980-1991."
Arrangement
The material is arranged as received from the donor.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Paul Stephen Galatowitsch, 2018
Biographical / Historical
Paul Stephen Galatowitsch received a PhD in Organizational and Institutional Sociology from Yale University in 1996. His dissertation was titled "An Institutional, Organizational, and Cultural Analysis of New Haven, Connecticut's Response to the AIDS Epidemic, 1980-1991." Dr. Galatowitsch specializes in the study of institutional, cultural, and political responses to illness and disease, in particular responses to HIV and AIDS.
Conditions Governing Access
The papers are open for research.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
AIDS (Disease) -- United States; AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects; AIDS (Disease) -- Law and legislation -- United States; AIDS (Disease) -- Prevention; AIDS (Disease) -- Treatment; Galatowitsch, Paul Stephen
- AIDS research
  - American College of Physicians, 1988–1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AIDS Clinic, 1983–1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AIDS Interfaith Network, Circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Archives, 1987–1989 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - The APT Foundation, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AIDS Response Research Group, research paper, Circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Australia AIDS information, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bibliography, New Haven newspapers, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - AIDS in Connecticut Annual Surveillance, 1991–1996 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Blaser, Rick, Circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut Department of Health, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1994–1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chief of Staff archives, 1983–1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Drafts, 1992–1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Drug Treatment, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Federal AIDS Bureau, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Focus group code sheet, data analysis code books, Circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Focus groups/crossroads, Circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Focus group, HIV+ New Haven, Circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Focus group, significant others, Circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General Accounting Office report, AIDS in Connecticut, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Haiti and AIDS, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Health Department, 1990–1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Human Investigation Application, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Interviews, 1993–1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Introduction- drafts, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Johnston paper, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - KAB- Centers for Disease Control, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kayal questionnaire, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Lifeprints, Bill Sabella, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Nurses, test counselors, Circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Levine fellowship, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Literature review, ACAD/Orbis searches, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Metaphors of AIDS, 1989–1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Isomorphism, Circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Organizational Effects of the Closet, Administrative Science Quarterly Remarks, 1997–1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General files and articles, 1993–1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Notebook on research, Circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Yale Library catalog searches, Circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Census data for Connecticut, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - HIV Infection, A Primary Care Approach, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - NEP section folder, chapter 4, 1987–1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - New Haven Mayor's Task Force on AIDS report, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - New Haven Mayor's Task Force on AIDS notes, 1989–1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New Haven general history, 1991–1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - National Institute of Health grants to Yale, 1980–1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Organizational charts, AIDS field and selected organizations, Circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Public Policy, AIDS, Connecticut, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Race and AIDS, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Race and Organizations, 1980s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Race and Organizations, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Soars comments on dissertation, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ryan White data, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - AIDS in Sweden, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Social movement papers, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Surveillance reports, 1991–1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vaccine trials, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - World AIDS Day, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - T-cell data, 1979–1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Yale School of Medicine Archives, 1988–1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Interviews, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - AIDS research, German report, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Writing, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Gay Men's Health Crisis Volunteer Manuel, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - AIDS organizations and health information, Circa 1980s (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Henriksson, Benny, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - World Health Organization, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  - Hospitals, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Health workers, 1987–1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Insurance, 1987–1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - IV articles, 1988–1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lawsuits, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Municritics, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Legal, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Military, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Prostitutes, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Public fear, 1986–1987 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Quarantine, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Schools, 1987–1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Religious, 1985–1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Research, 1987–1989 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Screening, 1986–1988 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Sex behavior, 1987–1988 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - State critics, 1987–1988 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Women, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Stat-Costs, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Workplace, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Azt and drugs, 1987–1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Blacks and Minorities, 1987–1989 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Blood, 1988–1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Children, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Discrimination, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Education, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Federal Critics, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Federal Policy, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Foreign, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Fund, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Gay behavior, 1986–1987 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Gay groups, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - General research articles, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - University reports, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Women and AIDS, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Reference books, bibliography, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Africa, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Canadian response, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Donation, 1986–1987 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - AIDS and moral duty, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Education, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Insurance, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - International response to AIDS, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Media responses, TV, plays, movies, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - People, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Heterosexual, 1983–1986 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Hospice extended care, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Housing, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Human T-lymphotrophic virus (HTLV-III), 1986 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - AIDS and insects, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - World Health Organization, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Psychiatric Response, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - San Francisco, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - AIDS and political campaigns, 1987–1988 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Private sector, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Supply and demand, generated and filled, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Supreme Court, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Prison, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - AIDS articles, 1989–1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - AIDS Interfaith Network, 1990–1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Elsie Cofield Interview, AIDS Interfaith office, 1990; 1 (Box 23)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - AIDS drugs, needle exchange, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - AIDS Project New Haven data, 1987–1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - AIDS Project New Haven board lists, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - AIDS Response Research Group, group history, 1990–1992 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - AIDS Response Research Group papers, 1990–1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Blood supply, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - CBO, New Haven community response to AIDS, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Johnston, Paul, 1993–1994 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Perrow, Chick, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation: Theory, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Dissertation drafts, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Drugs: AIDS Medicines, 1989–1993 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Fischer Report, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Gay identity/community papers, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Health Policy Seminar papers, 1985–1996 (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
  - Health Policy Seminar papers, 1985–1996 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - HIV+ publications, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Johnston paper and drafts, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper articles, 1989–1992 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Outreach articles and notes, 1987–1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Public Health Theory papers, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Washington D.C., AIDS, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Yale AIDS Colloquium Series, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Mayor's Task Force on AIDS, notes, 1986–1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Abstracts- AIDS articles, Circa 1990s (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Book reviews, 1991–1999 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Internet and sexuality, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Incoming emails, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing emails, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Ryan White Comprehensive AIDS Resources Emergency Act of 1990 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Book chapters, 1992–1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Book chapters, 1992–1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Organizational Theory articles, 1980–1996 (Box 14, Folder 2-5)
  - Jerusalem Star, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Gay Health surveys, 1983–1996 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Culture Reader for US, 1964–1995 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - Culture Theory- Art, 1960–1981 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Culture and AIDS articles, 1986–1993 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Culture and AIDS articles, 1986–1993 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Gay/lesbian and masculinity articles, 1989–1993 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Needle exchange, 1989–1995 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - AIDS articles by Yale faculty, 1986–1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - COSI seminar, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Social movements/interest groups, 1980–1991 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Organizations and AIDS, 1990–1992 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Organizations, 1978–1986 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Field notes, 1990–1991 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Field notes, 1990–1991 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Poverty, New Haven, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - News articles, 1985–1991 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Lisa Sullivan paper, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Interviews, 1993–1995 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Post-doc, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - AIDS service providers profile, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - AIDS grant/New Haven Foundation, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Steering Committee, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Steering Committee minutes, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Report to Mayor's Task Force on AIDS, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
  - Connecticut Responds to AIDS report, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Minutes/Agenda, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Ambulatory, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut AIDS Consortium needs assessment, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Case management, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Descriptions and CBDS, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Focus group, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Health Resources and Services Administration planning grant, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Long term home care, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Insurance information, Circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - An Assessment of AIDS Knowledge and Risk-taking Behaviors Among Active Out-of-Treatment IVDU's in New Haven, Connecticut, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Mental health, Circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Timeframe/Methodology file, Circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - West Haven AIDS Task Force report, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Project Solo, 1987–1988 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Hospital Care Working Committee problem statements, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Interviews, 1990–1994 (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Floppy disks, research files and data, 1980s-1990s; 14
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
    - T-Cell lab data (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - YACS (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Prospectus, YACS, comp notes and related material (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Prospectus, YACS, comp notes and related material (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - YAAR Home (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Hopwa.bk Nfocus, Nfo (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Final 4much (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - WP51 DOS files (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Courses, syllabus, YACS, and related material (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Untitled (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Untitled (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Untitled (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Bib back up (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - AIDS-MAURO (Box 22, Folder 14)